<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Function Literal</title>
		<description>Where I talk about code and stuff</description>
		<link>http://llkats.github.io</link>
		<atom:link href="http://llkats.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>gather the singletons</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s been two and a half years since I moved to San Francisco, and going to the Google SF office is no big deal anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was a funny realization -- it used to be such a big deal. But I walked in to a meetup last week feeling like I belonged there. And I did. I&amp;#39;ve visited the Google SF offices a few times; I&amp;#39;ve been to bunches of meetups at this point; I&amp;#39;ve been a professional front end engineer for nearly four years; I can hold my own in a conversation; I have no problem helping myself to free snacks and wine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I was hanging out with my SO, eating snacks and drinking wine, and I looked across the room at the woman who had ridden the elevator up with us. She was sitting by herself, studying her phone. A singleton to whom no one paid much attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It brought me right back to when I walked in to my first JS meetup in Chicago. I was just a student. I barely knew HTML and CSS, much less Javascript. The entire room was filled with men. I didn&amp;#39;t know what to expect, but I was crippled with doubt and anxiety. I felt like I stuck out like a sore thumb, and as the only woman in the room, I did. This was before I&amp;#39;d learned the confidence to turn to my neighbor and stick out my hand and introduce myself. Long before I realized that I belonged there as much as anyone and could carry that feeling into any situation I went into. Some guys glanced in my direction, but no one said anything to me. I slunk out as soon as the talks were done. I never went back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In that moment of hindsight, I realized what I should do. I got up without thinking too much about it, walked right over to her, and introduced myself. I asked her if she wanted to sit with us. She said yes without hesitation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It takes a huge measure of doing to walk into a new place and go up to any random stranger and just start talking. Especially if you&amp;#39;re a student, a newbie, a rando who&amp;#39;s never proved herself or written anything of consequence. (At least, that&amp;#39;s what you might think about yourself.) It&amp;#39;s enough to go to that strange place and take a snack or two and then just sit by oneself in the corner. That&amp;#39;s more than enough for one adventure. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Offering someone your name, inviting someone to join you -- it&amp;#39;s more than a courtesy. It&amp;#39;s a direct introduction into what feels like a very closed and very exclusive world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few more people joined us; friends of my SO, and their friends. When I saw another woman sit by herself, I went and gathered her into our group too. Both of those singletons lit up when I spoke to them; there was relief and excitement. They wanted to talk JS and meetups and living in the Bay Area, all the normal things one talks about at a meetup. They just needed a handhold, an opening. A single introduction. The feeling like they belonged. It was a simple gesture for me, but I think it really made a difference in both of their experiences that night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it&amp;#39;s important to remember the immense amount of courage someone needs in order to come to a meetup by his or herself. I think it&amp;#39;s important for established members in a programming community to make the next step easier: to welcome these singletons into our small groups, kickstart their senses of confidence, and teach them that they, too, belong.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2014 14:50:00 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>http://llkats.github.io/2014/01/10/gather-the-singletons</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://llkats.github.io/2014/01/10/gather-the-singletons</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>claiming the pavement</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;In California, bicyclists are legally allowed to take an entire lane to themselves. This is to ensure that a cyclist can always move out of danger if necessary; can take safe left turns with the flow of traffic; can move like a vehicle (albeit a slow-moving one).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting used to the power of taking a lane can take awhile, though. It&amp;#39;s scary, in a dense city like San Francisco, to feel safe on the road, even in a bike lane. There&amp;#39;s a good reason for that -- four bicyclists were killed in 2013, and over a dozen pedestrians. Sometimes it feels like the cars are out of control, that their drivers don&amp;#39;t have a sense of the immense power and responsibility they have when they&amp;#39;re behind the wheel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Events like Sunday Streets, where entire neighborhoods are shut down to cars for a day and people and rollerbladers and cyclists and razor scooters and rollerskaters take over the pavement, highlight the stark reality that cities are designed for cars, not people. It no longer seems obvious to me that of course we should have enormous swaths of space solely dedicated to the transit of vehicles, especially ones that have such lethal capacity. I don&amp;#39;t know what the solution is -- I&amp;#39;m not an urban planner or city designer -- but I am fascinated by the conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All I know is that when I take the lane on my bike, and drivers respect my space, I feel like I&amp;#39;m fully participating in the city. I feel in control of my transportation, and that feeling very empowering. I can take myself where I need to go, and don&amp;#39;t depend on anyone to do it for me. I &lt;strong&gt;do&lt;/strong&gt; depend on an infrastructure and community and rules of the road which supports me and other like me, a cyclist on a bike in a river of cars. Similarly, cars don&amp;#39;t exist in a vacuum: drivers depend upon society to maintain roads and stoplights, and trust that others will stop at a red light when they&amp;#39;re supposed to. Maybe being on a bike just makes that sense of interdependency all the more clear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over time, my comfort with taking a lane has grown. I get spooked every now and then by the news or by a close call with an carelessly opened door or a car that doesn&amp;#39;t signal its right turn, and when that happens, I take a break for a little bit. But I still seem to get back on the saddle again eventually. I think that confidence in riding is a powerful ally because I think it communicates to drivers that I won&amp;#39;t just pitch over or swerve into them. That I know what I&amp;#39;m doing, and deserve the same respect as any other vehicle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other night, I signalled a left turn at a four-way stop at which I had the right-of-way, and all the drivers waited patiently as I made it through the intersection. I was absorbed in the ride, with making the turn correctly and visibly, with the sound of tire on pavement, with the lane into which I was turning. I stayed in the center of the lane at the next intersection, so I could head straight when the light turned green, and at that red light, I realized that I hadn&amp;#39;t even thought about whether I should take the lane or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, I wasn&amp;#39;t afraid. I was just there, on the pavement, claiming my space.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2014 14:50:00 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>http://llkats.github.io/2014/01/10/claiming-pavement</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://llkats.github.io/2014/01/10/claiming-pavement</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>disconnection</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;This past weekend, I went offline from Thursday night until Sunday afternoon for some mental space. Here is what I missed while I was disconnected:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Things I Missed&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;chat.meatspac.es&quot;&gt;chat.meatspac.es&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;easy distractions while riding Muni or waiting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the instant gratification of reading new tweets/emails/instagrams/&amp;amp;c.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Things I Didn&amp;#39;t Miss&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;constant notification assaulting my attention&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the latest Twitter drama du jour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;looking up a random fact RIGHT THIS SECOND&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;not having any time to read&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a huge sprint at work, the internet was feeling more and more like an empty reward; I was depending on it too much for some sort of emotional connection and support. It was good to realize this and step away. I think I&amp;#39;ll be reducing the number of notifications I receive on my phone and computer, which felt like the healthiest part of the break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of sinking time into mindless clicking, I read books, worked on a couple projects, had lunch with my aunt, and sat zazen twice. I even worked through some of a code book (learning the ins and outs of &lt;a href=&quot;https://leanpub.com/marionette-gentle-introduction&quot;&gt;Marionette&lt;/a&gt; for work) and was kept on track by the empty pie slice symbol of the disconnected Wifi in my taskbar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, in the end, I don&amp;#39;t think I missed a whole lot. Though I am dying to get back on meatspace. Right after I finish this book.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2013 13:33:00 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>http://llkats.github.io/2013/11/24/disconnection</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://llkats.github.io/2013/11/24/disconnection</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>little epiphanies</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;So I was meditating on Saturday morning at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sfzc.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;SF Zen Center&lt;/a&gt;, and it was a tough session because I haven&amp;#39;t been practicing as consistently in the past few weeks as I had been over the summer and early fall, so my mind kept wandering and I kept not noticing it take off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was getting lost in my thoughts (it didn&amp;#39;t help that I was seated in the hallway outside the zendo, since I was too shy to enter the zendo late (but not too late)) and was surprised at how silent it is in the zendo compared to the hall, since there is the outside door opening and closing often, and voices echoing through the halls, and the sounds of meals being prepared and squishy sandal footsteps. There is so much to do lately, and I really needed to change the catbox and vaccuum at home, not to mention clean off my home desk, finish the book I&amp;#39;m reading so I can read the others that just came in the mail, continue making progress on the sprint at work, practice drawing, call my parents, ride my bike, work on my side projects, cure cancer, save the world, work out more, and maybe sleep, idk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thought arose: I&amp;#39;m here, so I should do what I came here to do. It was a moment of clarity in the midst of that squinting, tensing whirlwind of needs and to-dos. I&amp;#39;d gotten up early, showered, dressed, and hurried to the Center so I could sit on a cushion with dozens of other people and practice meditation. All the other things, obligations and wants, they could wait. I knew what they were; they&amp;#39;d be waiting when I was done. There is time enough for all of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a good thought. It wasn&amp;#39;t like I became enlightened or attained nirvana -- I still became distracted and my thoughts wandered back and away for the rest of the session. But it was a bit easier to come back to my breath and focus. Deliberation in action. Mindfulness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These little epiphanies are what keep me coming back to meditation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2013 23:36:00 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>http://llkats.github.io/2013/11/10/little-epiphanies</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://llkats.github.io/2013/11/10/little-epiphanies</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>New Beginnings, New Blog</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;The easy part is creating a blog in Jekyll, integrating a &lt;a href=&quot;http://house.github.io/tea/&quot;&gt;beautiful theme&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/house&quot;&gt;Allison House&lt;/a&gt;, and putting it on Github.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hard part is writing the blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome back to Function Literal. Hello world, indeed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2013 13:53:00 -0700</pubDate>
				<link>http://llkats.github.io/2013/10/06/new-beginnings-new-blog</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://llkats.github.io/2013/10/06/new-beginnings-new-blog</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
